Hello everyone, welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
Katarina- And my name is Katarina.
Katarina- 我是Katarina。
So today we've got a great upper intermediate level lesson for our learners and we're talking
今天我们为学习者准备了一节很棒的中高级课程，我们要讨论
about what?
什么呢？
Marco- Healthcare.
Marco- 医疗保健。
Katarina- Okay, this is a very important topic because it's been in the news recently, especially
Katarina- 好的，这是一个非常重要的话题，因为最近新闻里经常提到，尤其是
in the context of American politics.
在美国政治的背景下。
And so I don't know if you've heard things about this listeners, but the healthcare is
我不知道听众们有没有听说过这些，但医疗保健是一个
a very hot topic.
非常热门的话题。
Marco- Exactly.
Marco- 没错。
So basically what we're talking about is health insurance, whether it's private health insurance
所以我们主要讨论的是健康保险，无论是私人健康保险
or you know, like a standard national insurance program.
还是像标准的国家保险计划。
Katarina- Exactly.
Katarina- 没错。
And so your country might have a private option where you can pay a private company for insurance
你的国家可能有私人选项，你可以付钱给私人公司买保险，
or public option like England or Australia, where your country will actually provide healthcare
或者像英国或澳大利亚那样的公共选项，国家会为你提供医疗保健，
for you at no extra cost.
无需额外费用。
Marco- Very good.
Marco- 很好。
So it's an interesting topic.
这是个有趣的话题。
Why don't we jump directly into the dialogue and we'll be back to explain a couple of things.
我们直接进入对话吧，之后会回来解释一些内容。
Katarina- Hey, honey, how was your day?
Katarina- 嘿，亲爱的，今天过得怎么样？
Marco- It was all right.
Marco- 还行。
I ran into Bill and we got to talking for a while.
我碰到了Bill，我们聊了一会儿。
He's in a bit of a jam.
他有点麻烦。
Katarina- Why?
Katarina- 为什么？
What happened?
发生什么事了？
Marco- Well, his son had an accident.
Marco- 嗯，他儿子出了事故。
Bill doesn't have health insurance.
Bill没有健康保险。
This really got me thinking and I wondered if we shouldn't look into a couple of different
这让我想了很多，我在想我们是不是应该看看几个不同的
HMOs.
HMO。
Katarina- Yeah, you're right.
Katarina- 是啊，你说得对。
We aren't getting any younger and our kids are getting older.
我们都不再年轻了，孩子们也在长大。
Marco- Exactly.
Marco- 没错。
I searched on the web and found a couple of HMOs with low copays and good coverage.
我在网上搜了一下，找到了几个共付额低、覆盖范围好的HMO。
The deductibles are low too.
免赔额也很低。
Katarina- Sounds good.
Katarina- 听起来不错。
Although, do you think we can qualify for insurance?
不过，你觉得我们能符合保险资格吗？
Those insurance companies are real pirates when it comes to money.
那些保险公司在钱的问题上真是强盗。
Marco- Well, we don't have any pre-existing illnesses or conditions, so we should be fine.
Marco- 嗯，我们没有任何已有的疾病或状况，所以应该没问题。
Katarina- I wish our company or country provided us with healthcare.
Katarina- 我真希望我们的公司或国家能提供医疗保健。
Marco- Not in a million years.
Marco- 绝不可能。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So a lot of interesting vocab here.
这里有很多有趣的词汇。
Why don't we take a look at it real fast in Language Takeaway.
我们快速看一下“语言要点”部分吧。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Katarina- Okay, Marco, this first phrase or acronym actually is three words that go together,
Katarina- 好的，Marco，第一个短语或者说缩写实际上是三个词组成的，
HMO, and they're very, very common when you're talking about healthcare.
HMO，在谈论医疗保健时非常非常常见。
Marco- Right.
Marco- 对。
So an HMO means health maintenance organization.
所以HMO的意思是健康维护组织。
Katarina- Okay, and so this is a part of the health insurance topic where we're talking
Katarina- 好的，这是健康保险话题的一部分，我们讨论的是
about a company that will provide health insurance.
提供健康保险的公司。
Marco- Right, so it's a company that provides health insurance, basically.
Marco- 对，基本上就是提供健康保险的公司。
And if you go up to an HMO, some of the information that you'll receive is, for example, what
如果你去找HMO，你会收到一些信息，比如
your co-pay will be.
你的共付额是多少。
Katarina- Okay, so sometimes with a private option, when you pay a company to give you
Katarina- 好的，有时在私人选项下，当你付钱给公司买健康保险时，
health insurance, you can get a lower rate if you help pay for some of your care.
如果你自己承担部分医疗费用，你可以得到更低的费率。
So for example, a co-pay on a broken arm might be $20, but you pay $20, that's your
比如，治疗手臂骨折的共付额可能是20美元，你付20美元，这就是你的
co-pay, and your health insurance company pays the rest.
共付额，你的健康保险公司付剩下的。
And so sometimes co-pays are really high, they're really big, and that's kind of a bad
有时共付额很高，很大一笔，这就不太划算，
deal because if you hurt yourself, you don't want to pay a lot.
因为如果你受伤了，你不想付很多钱。
But sometimes there's no co-pay, in which case your company will pay for all of the
但有时没有共付额，这种情况下你的公司会支付所有
coverage.
覆盖的费用。
Marco- All right, so another very similar word is a deductible.
Marco- 好的，另一个非常相似的词是免赔额。
Katarina- Okay, so a deductible is something that is fixed and it's in your insurance policy.
Katarina- 好的，免赔额是固定的，写在你的保险单里。
That means in the contract that you make with the insurance company, the deductible will
也就是说在你和保险公司签订的合同里，会写明免赔额
be stated.
是多少。
So for example, my insurance plan, I have maybe a $500 deductible.
比如，我的保险计划可能有500美元的免赔额。
That means that in any situation, I get hurt or I get sick, I pay for the first $500 of
这意味着在任何情况下，我受伤或生病了，我先支付前500美元的
care and then my insurance company pays for the rest.
医疗费用，然后我的保险公司支付剩下的。
So if I have to have a $1,000 surgery, I pay $500 and then my insurance company pays the
所以如果我需要做1000美元的手术，我付500美元，然后我的保险公司付
other $500.
另外500美元。
Marco- Okay, very good.
Marco- 好的，很好。
And well, you have these deductibles and everything and that depends on your coverage, right?
嗯，你有这些免赔额之类的，这取决于你的覆盖范围，对吧？
So coverage, how much the HMO covers you.
所以覆盖范围，就是HMO覆盖你的程度。
Katarina- That's right.
Katarina- 没错。
And so you can find this also in your contract with your insurance company and coverage will
你也可以在保险公司的合同里找到这个，覆盖范围会
include or not include something.
包括或不包括某些东西。
So coverage, for example, in a healthcare plan does not usually include your teeth.
比如，医疗保健计划中的覆盖范围通常不包括牙齿。
That's a separate kind of insurance.
那是另一种保险。
But a coverage can include emergency evacuation from a situation or ambulances, for example.
但覆盖范围可以包括紧急撤离或救护车，比如。
And so coverage is what is included in your insurance plan.
所以覆盖范围就是你的保险计划中包含的内容。
Marco- Okay, very good.
Marco- 好的，很好。
And our last word for today is to qualify for.
今天我们最后一个词是“符合资格”。
Katarina- All right.
Katarina- 好的。
So you might have heard this phrase before in the context of sports or academics.
你可能在体育或学术的语境中听过这个短语。
So he qualified for a scholarship or she qualified for the varsity volleyball team.
比如他符合奖学金资格，或者她符合校排球队资格。
But in this case, to qualify for is to be able to use.
但在这里，“符合资格”意思是能够使用。
Marco- To be eligible for.
Marco- 有资格。
Katarina- To be eligible for.
Katarina- 有资格。
Marco- So sometimes HMOs like in, for example, the United States will not accept a person
Marco- 所以有时HMO，比如在美国，不会接受一个
who has maybe some health problems already because that would be too much of a risk,
已经有健康问题的人，因为那样风险太大，
right?
对吧？
For the company.
对公司来说。
All right.
好的。
Katarina- That's right.
Katarina- 没错。
Or you could qualify for a reduced rate because you have a very good health history.
或者你可能因为健康状况很好而符合降低费率的资格。
Marco- Okay.
Marco- 好的。
So this is very interesting.
这非常有趣。
And we have a couple of other phrases that are very related to this language.
我们还有几个与这些语言非常相关的短语。
So why don't we move on now to Fluency Builder.
所以我们继续看“流利度提升”部分。
Katarina- Fluency Builder.
Katarina- 流利度提升。
Marco- All right.
Marco- 好的。
So in Fluency Builder today, let's take a look at our first phrase.
在今天的“流利度提升”中，我们来看第一个短语。
We got to talking for a while.
我们聊了一会儿。
Katarina- Okay.
Katarina- 好的。
We could say, for example, we started talking or we were talking for a while.
我们可以说，比如，我们开始聊天，或者我们聊了一会儿。
But this is a very spoken language kind of phrase where we'd say, we got to talking.
但这是一个非常口语化的短语，我们会说“我们聊了起来”。
Marco- Right.
Marco- 对。
So it's not really grammatically correct because you would say we started talking.
所以从语法上讲不太正确，因为你会说“我们开始聊天”。
But sometimes people say we got to talking.
但有时人们会说“我们聊了起来”。
So we got into a conversation, right?
意思是我们进入了对话，对吧？
Katarina- That's right.
Katarina- 没错。
And usually it's about something.
而且通常是关于某件事。
So we could say, yeah, we got to talking about how we both went to the same high school.
所以我们可以说，是啊，我们聊了起来，关于我们都上过同一所高中。
Or we got to talking about this movie that we both saw.
或者我们聊了起来，关于我们都看过的那部电影。
Marco- Okay.
Marco- 好的。
Very good.
很好。
And well, they got to talking for a while and apparently his friend was in a bit of
嗯，他们聊了一会儿，显然他的朋友有点
a jam.
麻烦。
Katarina- Okay.
Katarina- 好的。
Jam is a food.
果酱是一种食物。
You can eat it.
你可以吃它。
You put it on bread.
你把它涂在面包上。
Marco- Like marmalade, right?
Marco- 就像橘子酱一样，对吧？
Katarina- Exactly.
Katarina- 没错。
And to be in a jam is a fix or a difficult situation.
而“陷入困境”是指一个棘手或困难的处境。
So it has a very different meaning and I want to warn you about that first.
所以它的意思完全不同，我想先提醒你这一点。
But to be in a jam or to be in a bit of a jam is to be stuck.
但“陷入困境”或“有点麻烦”就是被卡住了。
Marco- Okay.
Marco- 好的。
So you're in a difficult situation.
所以你处于一个困难的境地。
You have some problem.
你遇到了一些问题。
Katarina- Yeah.
Katarina- 是的。
So, Marco, I'm in a bit of a jam here.
所以，Marco，我这儿有点麻烦。
Can I get your help with something?
你能帮我个忙吗？
Marco- All right.
Marco- 好吧。
Very good.
很好。
Okay.
好的。
And then the guy was talking about insurance and he said, this really got me thinking.
然后那个人在谈论保险时说了，这真的让我开始思考。
So we got the verb got again there.
所以我们又看到了动词“got”。
Katarina- All right.
Katarina- 好的。
So got me thinking.
所以“got me thinking”。
That means I started thinking about something.
意思是我开始思考某件事。
So when we were talking about jam a minute ago, it got me thinking about how much I love
所以当我们刚才谈论果酱时，这让我开始思考我有多喜欢
breakfast.
早餐。
Marco- Very good.
Marco- 很好。
So you would use it in that way, right?
所以你会这样用它，对吧？
Katarina- Like it reminded me.
Katarina- 就像它提醒了我。
Marco- It reminded me or I started to really think about something.
Marco- 它提醒了我，或者我开始认真思考某件事。
Okay.
好的。
And our last phrase is a pre-existing illness.
我们最后一个短语是“已有疾病”。
Katarina- All right.
Katarina- 好的。
So to exist is to be, to be around, pre-existing means existing before something else.
所以“存在”就是“是”或“存在”，“已有”意思是之前就存在。
And so you often hear this in terms of insurance when someone asks you about your pre-existing
所以你经常在保险方面听到这个，当有人问你关于你的已有
condition.
状况时。
So that means if I'm signing up for an insurance plan, health insurance plan, and I have an
也就是说，如果我正在注册一个保险计划，健康保险计划，并且我跟你Marco有个
interview with you, Marco, and you ask me this question.
面试，你问我这个问题。
Marco- What is your pre-existing condition?
Marco- 你的已有状况是什么？
Katarina- That means what diseases or health problems do I have right now?
Katarina- 意思是我现在有什么疾病或健康问题？
Prior to signing up for this insurance.
在注册这个保险之前。
And I say, Oh, I don't have any.
然后我说，哦，我没有任何问题。
And you're very happy because that means I'll be cheap.
你会很高兴，因为这意味着我会很便宜。
But if I say, Oh, I have diabetes, then that is something that the insurance companies
但如果我说，哦，我有糖尿病，那就是保险公司
don't like because it's expensive.
不喜欢的事情，因为它很贵。
Marco- Right.
Marco- 对。
Because you're more probable of getting sick or something like that.
因为你更可能生病或类似的情况。
Katarina- Right.
Katarina- 对。
So diabetes or cancer or Lyme disease, these are all pre-existing conditions.
所以糖尿病、癌症或莱姆病，这些都是已有状况。
And usually pre-existing conditions are diseases or health problems that you have that won't
通常已有状况是指你有的、不会
go away.
消失的疾病或健康问题。
Marco- Okay.
Marco- 好的。
Very good.
很好。
All right.
好的。
So we have a lot of words, a lot of phrases here.
所以我们这里有很多单词，很多短语。
Let's listen to the dialogue one last time and we'll be back.
让我们最后听一遍对话，然后我们会回来。
Hey, honey, how was your day?
嘿，亲爱的，你今天过得怎么样？
It was all right.
还行。
I ran into Bill and we got to talking for a while.
我碰见了比尔，我们聊了一会儿。
He's in a bit of a jam.
他有点麻烦。
Why?
为什么？
What happened?
发生什么事了？
Well, his son had an accident.
嗯，他儿子出了事故。
Bill doesn't have health insurance.
比尔没有健康保险。
This really got me thinking.
这真的让我开始思考。
And I wondered if we shouldn't look into a couple of different HMOs.
我想我们是不是应该看看几个不同的健康维护组织。
Yeah, you're right.
是的，你说得对。
We aren't getting any younger and our kids are getting older.
我们都不再年轻了，孩子们也越来越大。
Exactly.
没错。
I searched on the web and found a couple of HMOs with low copays and good coverage.
我在网上搜了一下，找到了几个共付额低、覆盖范围好的健康维护组织。
The deductibles are low too.
免赔额也很低。
Sounds good.
听起来不错。
Although, do you think we can qualify for insurance?
不过，你觉得我们能符合保险资格吗？
Those insurance companies are real pirates when it comes to money.
那些保险公司在钱的问题上真是强盗。
Well, we don't have any pre-existing illnesses or conditions, so we should be fine.
嗯，我们没有任何已有疾病或状况，所以应该没问题。
I wish our company or country provided us with health care.
我希望我们公司或国家能提供医疗保健。
Not in a million years.
绝不可能。
All right.
好的。
So the health care issue is pretty heated debate now in the United States because many
所以医疗保健问题现在在美国是一个相当激烈的辩论，因为很多人
people don't have health care and it's not very accessible, right?
没有医疗保健，而且它不太容易获得，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
It's a huge debate because it's very, very divided by party lines.
这是一个巨大的辩论，因为它被党派路线严重分裂。
We say there's the Republicans on the right and there's the Democrats on the left and
我们说右边有共和党，左边有民主党，
the Democrats want a public health care option.
民主党想要一个公共医疗保健选项。
They want health care to be available for everyone for free.
他们希望医疗保健对每个人免费开放。
And many of them do.
他们中的很多人都这样想。
And a lot of Republicans say, no, it should be private because if it's private, there's
很多共和党人说，不，它应该是私有的，因为如果是私有的，就有
competition and that means there's better health care.
竞争，这意味着有更好的医疗保健。
And so there's a really big debate and people are getting very angry about it.
所以有一个非常大的辩论，人们对此非常生气。
Yeah.
是的。
And I think it's something that's very interesting and most importantly, seeing the difference
我认为这是一件非常有趣的事情，最重要的是，看到世界各地
of health care systems around the world, right?
医疗保健系统的差异，对吧？
So for example, our listeners, they are from everywhere in the world.
例如，我们的听众来自世界各地。
So we would like to know what the health care system is like there.
所以我们想知道那里的医疗保健系统是什么样的。
Do you have free universal health care in your country or do you also have to pay for
你们国家有免费的全民医疗保健，还是你们也必须向
private companies or private health insurance?
私人公司或私人健康保险付费？
And if you have one or the other system, do you think it's a good thing?
如果你有其中一种系统，你认为这是好事吗？
Do you think it's a bad thing?
你认为这是坏事吗？
What do you think needs some work?
你觉得哪些方面需要改进？
Right.
对。
I definitely agree with universal health care.
我绝对赞同全民医疗保健。
I think it's a relief because it's like one thing less to worry about.
我认为这是一种解脱，因为少了一件需要担心的事。
I can't imagine like, you know, if I don't have health care right now and I'm not covered
我无法想象，比如，如果我现在没有医疗保健，没有被
by a private company and something happens to me tomorrow, then you know, what's going
私人公司覆盖，明天我出了什么事，那么你知道，会发生
to happen?
什么？
And I think it's a basic human right personally.
我个人认为这是基本人权。
So I think it's in the best interests of a country to invest in it because it means that
所以我认为投资于它符合国家的最佳利益，因为这意味着
their people are more productive and happier.
他们的人民更高效、更快乐。
And healthier.
也更健康。
Yeah.
是的。
All right.
好的。
So that's all the time we have for today.
所以我们今天的时间就到这里。
Be sure to come to EnglishPod.com.
一定要来EnglishPod.com。
Leave your questions and comments and we'll see you guys there.
留下你的问题和评论，我们会在那里见你们。
Bye everyone.
大家再见。
Take care.
保重。